[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Live Forever]
[Episode 8]
So,
you took the surname Ning because of me?
Then...
he was already obsessed with me back then.
Narcissistic personality.
Is there any cure for that?
From a professional perspective...
it's hard to say.
It's really hard to say.
But I truly waited a very, very long time
for the day we reunited.
[Duansi Palace]
Who are you?
Ning Changyue of the Yulin Guard.
Greetings, Your Highness Princess Ningjia.
Yulin Guard?
What do you want with me?
This is for you.
If you're thirsty, hungry, or in pain,
just blow this whistle to find me.
It's you.
You became a Yulin Guard.
Doing quite well for yourself, huh?
You've grown taller
and stronger.
You seem well-trained, too.
If not for Your Highness saving my life that day,
I probably wouldn't have survived.
Your Highness,
I am here to repay that debt.
Repay the debt?
Is this how you repay a debt?
That hurt like hell.
Forget it. Don't take it to heart.
Anyway, I was just
being a bit nosy.
Make a deal with me.
Your Highness.
Teach me martial arts,
riding and archery.
Tell me,
what the price of grain is
and how much cloth costs
in the West Market and East District.
How can a painting
or a piece of calligraphy
be exchanged
for enough copper coins to survive?
In exchange,
I can teach you how to read and draw,
if you want to.
May I?
Of course.
I'm willing to serve Your Highness.
But what I hope is,
not a guard serving a princess,
but a person named Ning Changyue
teaching a person named Song Yiqiu
what it truly means to have a life.
To have a life?
Your Highness,
I don't understand.
Call me Song Yiqiu!
Alright.
Song...
Song Yiqiu.
It's been a long time,
Ning Changyue.
To me back then,
I didn't know
what freedom and having a life meant.
But if she wanted them,
I would definitely give them to her.
By the way,
call me anytime.
Got it.
Having been in this palace for so long,
I can't believe I still trusted someone so easily.
I made this especially for you.
Build up your strength first.
If you can't even draw the bow,
how can you practice archery?
You certainly get straight to the point.
Didn't you say you wanted to practice archery?
Here.
Like this.
Raise your arm.
Drop shoulders.
Song Yiqiu.
Calm the mind.
This is osmanthus cake from the West Market.
The West Market?
The West Market is bustling and noisy.
Vendors gather there.
It's packed with a constant stream of people.
It has the liveliest earthly atmosphere.
Qiu,
this is a kite from the East District.
The East District?
The East District is full of workshops.
There are many tailoring,
blacksmith, and silversmith workshops.
What are you drawing?
You look so focused.
Nothing.
Just casually sketching the palace scenery.
You're drawing the imperial kitchen...
Its side door is for servants,
so it's rarely patrolled.
You observe
quite carefully.
You're not drawing ordinary palace scenery.
You're trying to find a way out,
aren't you?
How can you fail at the simplest
tracing?
I'm sorry.
You don't need to grip the brush so hard.
Once your heart is steady,
your brush will be steady.
Relax your hand a bit.
I'll hold your hand,
and we'll draw together.
Focus.
Ning Changyue,
come here now!
Over the years, using my memory
and overheard information, I drew this map.
Look,
is this palace map accurate?
Pretty much.
At 7:45 PM,
the guards in the east corridor change shifts.
There will be a window of one incense stick's time.
Here.
The alchemy room shifts every hour.
There will be a brief moment of chaos during the shift.
If we go this way,
and if all goes well,
we can leave the palace smoothly.
Qiu,
I'll take you somewhere.
Only when looking from here do I realize
just how huge the palace is.
A shooting star!
We are so lucky.
Yeah.
So lucky.
Make a wish, quick!
Hurry!
♪ Parting clouds to pluck the moon ♪
♪ Brewing a pot of bygone years ♪
♪ Cold candlelight ♪
♪ Waking the shadow to soothe my sorrow ♪
♪ Drunk for three live with no dream returned ♪
♪ How to break this illusion without letting go? ♪
♪ Returning to wander the mortal realm ♪
What did you wish for?
♪ Like her like yesterday unchanging ♪
It won't come true if I say it out loud.
♪ Carved hairpin filled with endless sighs ♪
♪ Fate sees through my hidden thoughts ♪
Stingy.
♪ Like promise like regret like love ♪
♪ Loving and hurting yet meeting too late ♪
Why don't you ask
what I wished for?
Freedom.
♪ Who holds more regret in this entanglement? ♪
You've said it three thousand times.
It's etched into your bones.
Qiu,
on the seventh of next month,
I will get you out of the palace.
At 7:45 PM,
the guards in the east corridor change shifts.
There is a gap of one incense stick's time.
The seventh?
This is...
On the seventh of next month,
the higher-ups have shown mercy
and are letting you leave the palace.
Come over here and register your names.
That's great. We can finally leave!
Thank you, my lord!
Don't rush.
One at a time.
I can finally go home.
My lord!
Have mercy, my lord!
I can't leave the palace.
I can't leave!
Thank you, my lord.
The medicine testers who survived the last failed trials
will be dismissed from the palace on the seventh.
Xiaoyuan is one of them.
You will swap clothes with her
and take her place to leave the palace.
I swap with her?
No way.
The chance for a medicine tester to leave alive is so rare.
How could I steal her chance to live
just for my own freedom?
Your Highness,
I am doing this willingly.
I entered the palace
to look for my long-lost brother.
Since he is still missing,
I cannot leave.
As long as you can safely leave the palace on the seventh,
I will hide her for a while.
Once the heat dies down,
I'll find her a position in the palace.
This way, she can make a living
and continue looking for her brother.
This palace isn't that big.
As long as she stays,
they will meet again someday.
The freedom you want
is right in front of you.
After you leave the palace later,
your new identity documents
and transit tokens
are buried under the third old locust tree.
Turn left after exiting,
go through two alleys,
and when you reach the third narrow door,
push it open and you'll find our contact.
Carriages, horses, and food,
along with the route to Nanjing, are all arranged.
Okay.
What about you?
Your Highness,
are you trying to elope with someone?